Guide to the Inge Morath Photographs and Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographs and Papers from the Morath-Miller Home, 1940-2005; Series III; 6.34; (16 boxes)
  - Audiovisual Material
    - Audiocassettes, 1960, undated; 8
      Audiocassettes: "Chinese", "Douglas Dunn poetry/Philip Larkin poetry," "Vadim Andreyev reads Pasternack/Vadim...reads M. Audel poems," "Música Antigua Española S. XIII SXV Cantigas de Alfonso X el Sabio," "Orf, Radio Wien, Signale/Zeitgenosson," "Hindemith/Ibert," "Tolstoy Foundation captions guide/Sounds, Snow Brook," "Red Army Chorus, Paris 1960"
    - Videocassettes, undated; 2 videocassettes (S-VHS)
      2 S-VHS videocassettes: "Inge Morath Practice tape, L. A. [Fl?].," "Inge test roll, untitled Venice apartment"
    - Audiotape, 1971-1973; 1; reel to reel tapes
      "TV tape May 7th," "Inge interview, UHF Ch 31, UBC 88-30 1/19/71/ In and out of focus, 5-7-73"
  - Correspondence
    - "A" General, 1976 (Box 704)
    - "B" General, 1965-1978 (Box 704)
    - Berlin, 1980-1995 (Box 704)
    - "C" General, 1973-1978 (Box 704)
    - Carlisle, Olga, 1977-1996 (Box 704)
    - Clarke, Martha, 1989 (Box 704)
    - "D-F" General, 1977-1978 (Box 704)
    - "Famous people", 1972-1975 (Box 704)
    - Friends, 1990 (Box 704)
    - "G-H" General, 1977-1978 (Box 704)
    - Gray, Francine du Plessix, 1976-1991 (Box 705)
    - "I-J" General, 1977 (Box 705)
    - International, 1978-2001; 5 (Box 705)
    - Israel, 1977 (Box 705)
    - "K-L" General, 1977, undated (Box 705)
    - "M" General, 1962-1977 (Box 706)
    - Magnum, 1969-1993; 3 (Box 706)
    - Mandelshtam, 1968-2001 (Box 706)
    - "N" General, 1976 (Box 706)
    - Osborne, Robert, 1970-1992; 3 (Box 706)
    - "P-Q" General, 1977 (Box 706)
    - PEN Club, 1973 (Box 706)
    - PEN Congress N.Y. Viking Press, 1972, 1985 (Box 706)
    - "R" General, 1976-1978 (Box 706)
    - "S-T" General, 1963-1978 (Box 707)
    - "S.A.", 1956 (Box 707)
    - "V-Z" General, 1963-1978 (Box 707)
    - Van Eekelen, Adrienne, 1991-1992 (Box 707)
    - "Vienna friends", 1990-1994 (Box 707)
    - Wedding congratulations, 1962; 2 (Box 707)
    - Miscellaneous, 1972 (Box 707)
    - General correspondence, 1962-1990; 8 (Box 708)
    - General correspondence, 1993-2001; 9 (Box 709)
    - "Postcards: the images from which I learn", 1972-1978 (Box 709)
    - "IM saved postcards", undated (Box 709)
  - Writings
    This subseries includes notes and typescripts written by Morath.
    - "Berlin, War," typescripts, 1989 (Box 710)
    - "Burt Glinn: IM intro," typescript, undated (Box 710)
    - "Connecticut book," "Woolf," notes, undated (Box 710)
    - "In the country," typescript, 1970 (Box 710)
    - "Lilac and Ashes," typescript, undated (Box 710)
    - "Notes on creating.. .", undated (Box 710)
    - "On plays and creating," notes and drafts, circa 1972 (Box 710)
    - "Photographing A's projects," typescript, undated (Box 710)
    - "Portraits," "Foreword: Portfolio," typescripts, undated (Box 710)
    - "Refugees, Gaza," story list notes, undated (Box 710)
    - "Reply to bio request," letter, 1984 (Box 710)
    - "Tokyo show," notes, 1996 (Box 710)
    - "Travel diary to Reno," typescript, 1960 (Box 710)
    - "Woman," typescripts, 1973 (Box 710)
    - Writings and correspondence, 1988-1990 (Box 710)
    - "On IM," (photocopy), undated (Box 710)
  - Travel
    This subseries Includes travel notebooks, address books, and visiting cards.
    - Paris notebooks, 1954-1956; 3 (Box 710)
    - Roxbury, Woodbury, 1964 (Box 710)
    - Spain, 1954 (Box 710)
    - Tunisia, 1956 (Box 710)
    - Venice, circa 1953 (Box 710)
    - France, Barcelona, 1956-1958; 2 (Box 710)
    - Address books, 1944-1981, undated; 8 (Box 711)
    - Visiting cards and addresses, undated (Box 711)
    - Visiting cards, 1978-1990; 6 (Box 712)
    - Visiting cards, 1950, undated; 4 (Box 713)
  - Exhibits
    - Exhibits, invitations, catalogs, 1957-1995; 8 (Box 714)
    - "Morath-Romania, original RGB press web", undated
    - Exhibits, invitations, catalogs, 1994-2005; 3 (Box 715)
    - Berlin show, 1996 March (Box 715)
  - Other Material
    - "Keepsakes," dried rose, undated (Box 715)
    - Collected stamps, 1955-1959 (Box 715)
    - Robert Osborn, artworks, 1976, undated (Box 716)
    - Galerie Fotohof, poster, 1982 (Box 716)
    - The Post, 1964 February (Box 716)
- Audiovisual Material, 1960-2004; Series IV; 3.92; (8 boxes)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Boxes 717-718 (audiocassettes): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Box 718 (reel-to-reel tape): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Boxes 719-722 (videocassettes): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Box 723 (motion picture): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Series IV is organized into four subseries: Sound Recordings, Video Recordings, Films, and Associated Material.
  This series consists of sound recordings, videocassettes, and films by or about Morath, and chiefly of interviews with her and documentation of her exhibitions.
  - Sound Recordings
    - Audiocassettes from Series III
      - "Chinese", undated; 1 (Box 717)
      - "Douglas Dunn poetry/Philip Larkin poetry", 1 (Box 717)
      - "Vadim Andreyev reads Pasternack/Vadim...reads M. Audel poems", undated; 1 (Box 717)
      - "Música Antigua Española S. XIII SXV Cantigas de Alfonso X el Sabio", undated; 1 (Box 717)
      - "Orf, Radio Wien, Signale/Zeitgenosson", undated; 1 (Box 717)
      - "Hindemith/Ibert", undated; 1 (Box 717)
      - "Tolstoy Foundation captions guide/Sounds Snow Brook", undated; 1 (Box 717)
      - "Red Army chorus, Paris", 1960; 1 (Box 717)
    - "Orf-Landesstudio Hamburg, in Kultur Kompass, Interview M. Mayraker liber 1. Morath retrospective in Fotohof," from Series II, 1982 August; 1 (Box 717)
    - "Original interview/Interview which was aired. Elizabeth Hellman is interviewed by Peggy Dominique for WBAI Radio and the Reading series at Ceres," from Series V, undated; 1 (Box 717)
    - "1 Philadelphia" from Series V., undated; 1 (Box 717)
    - Untitled, from Series V, undated; 1 (Box 717)
    - "TV tape May 7th" and "Inge interview, UHF Ch 31, UBC 88-30 1/19/71/ In and out of focus, 5-7-73," from Series III, 1971, 1973; 1 reel to reel audio tape (Box 718)
  - Video Recordings
    - "New, used and improved: Art for the 80's," Channel 2 (Nightwatch), The Today Show, circa 1980; GENMSS996_0001; 1; 00:22:08 (Box 719, Item barcode 39002102310019)
    - "Kennedy Honors, Erbitte Zuruck, Dr. Morath", undated; GENMSS996_0002; 1; 02:06:50 (Box 719, Item barcode 39002102310027)
    - "Exposition Inge Morath "España Años 50" Mayo-Junio 1995, Duracion: 12'", 1995 May-1995 June; GENMSS996_0003; 1; 00:12:34 (Box 719, Item barcode 39002102310035)
      Departamento de Educación - Gobierno de Navarra
    - "Inge Morath 'on the rocks,' 5:30 silent", undated; GENMSS996_0004; 1; 00:06:00 (Box 719, Item barcode 39002102310043)
    - "NDR talk show mit Inge Morath vom 7.10.1994, 2 hr 30 min", GENMSS996_0005; 1; 02:30:25 (Box 719, Item barcode 39002102310050)
    - "Achtung Kultur, Inge Morath", undated; GENMSS996_0006; 1; 00:08:43 (Box 719, Item barcode 39002102310068)
    - "Berlin Lecture, NTSC", undated; GENMSS996_0007; 1; 00:54:46 (Box 719, Item barcode 39002102310076)
    - "Louise Bourgeois, Arena Films, BBC London, director: Nigel Finch", 1994; GENMSS996_0008; 1; 00:56:14 (Box 719, Item barcode 39002102310084)
    - "Kids film, copyright Inge Morath", 1991; GENMSS996_0009; 1; 01:25:34 (Box 719, Item barcode 39002102310092)
    - "Inge Morath-Letzte Reise", 2003; GENMSS996_0010; 1; 01:33:59 (Box 719, Item barcode 39002102310100)
    - "Sunday Morning, Women Photographers 2/2/97, transition from tradition to modern times...", 1997 February 2; GENMSS996_0011; 1; 00:07:31
      "Cued to 5:00, Inge panel [dia]"
    - "Berliner Lektionen 09.10.94 Inge Morath: 'Ich traue meinen Augen...' Mitschnitt aus dem Renaisance Theater Berlin, Copy ca.60 min.", 1994 October 9; GENMSS996_0012; 1; 00:55:50
    - "USMA Rhode Scholars", undated; GENMSS996_0013; 1; 00:18:00
    - "Artscene on Long Island with Shirley Rom[?], Inge Morath", undated; GENMSS996_0014; 1; 00:32:03
      "Overlaps w/ "Copyright" (also by S.E.) early Scene: I & A in kitchen and revisiting Chelsea"
    - "Inge Morath: Portrait of a Fotographer" "NTSC, color appr. 60 min.", 1991; GENMSS996_0015; 1; 00:57:12
    - "Inge Morath: Pamplona shoot exhibition: Tucson, Arizona, PBS Report", 1997 December; GENMSS996_0016; 1; 00:06:53
    - "Magnum 40th Anniversary", 1987; GENMSS996_0017; 1; 01:59:37
      BBC Films #1: The Magnum Story: Decisive Moments, 62.5 minutes; BBC Films #2: The Magnum Story: The Savage Years, 55 minutes
    - " Magnum Photos - Ein Mythos ändert sich, Reiner Holzemer Film und TV Produktion", 1999; GENMSS996_0018; 1; 01:29:09
    - "WIR Frauen", 1999 August 29; GENMSS996_0019; 1; 00:26:10
    - " Kulturweltspiegel vom 4.4.1993" - "(Not IM)", 1993 April 4; GENMSS996_0020; 1; 00:38:57
    - "Copyright by Inge Morath," von Sabine Eckard. 85 min. NTSC dt. UT Kick Film (copy 1 of 2), 1994; GENMSS996_0021; 1; 01:25:32 (Box 721, Item barcode 39002102310217)
    - "Copyright by Inge Morath," von Sabine Eckard. 85 min. NTSC dt. UT Kick Film (copy 2 of 2), 1994; GENMSS996_0022; 1; 01:25:25 (Box 721, Item barcode 39002102310225)
    - "Inge Morath, Kick Films, US to US, 2 copies", 1991; GENMSS996_0023; 1; 01:25:31 (Box 721, Item barcode 39002102310233)
    - "Copy Inge "Kick" film, copyright by Inge Morath, 1991; GENMSS996_0024; 1; 01:25:42 (Box 721, Item barcode 39002102310241)
    - "Kick Film & Fernsehproductions GMBH" (copy 1 of 2), 1991; GENMSS996_0025; 1; 01:28:05 (Box 721, Item barcode 39002102310258)
    - "Kick Film & Fernsehproductions GMBH" (copy 2 of 2), 1991; GENMSS996_0026; 1; 01:27:38 (Box 721, Item barcode 39002102310266)
    - "Arthur Miller @ Howard Greenberg Gallery (Raw Footage) May 26th 2004", 2004 May 26; GENMSS996_0027; 1; 00:53:14 (Box 721, Item barcode 39002102310274)
    - "Imagine, Arthur Miller" BBC Post Production, AS Master 525 NTSC, 2004 November 27; GENMSS996_0028; 1; 01:16:08 (Box 721, Item barcode 39002102310282)
    - "Inge Morath practice tape, L. A. Fl.," from Series III., undated; 1 videocassettes (S-VHS) (Box 722)
    - "Inge test roll, untitled Venice apartment," from Series III., undated; 1 videocassettes (S-VHS) (Box 722)
  - Films
    - "RS movie slow I and II run on 54," From Series II., undated; 1 (Box 723)
    - "Spanish stills," From Series II., undated; 1 (Box 723)
    - "Sketch book for [?] Series. I bad cou[?] held interview no subjects," From Series II., undated; 1 (Box 723)
    - "Darmstadt," From Series V., undated; 1 (Box 723)
    - "Darmstadt 2," From Series V., undated; 1 (Box 723)
    - "Schirmeck Wishes," From Series V., undated; 1 (Box 723)
    - Untitled, From Series V., 1992 October 16; 1 (Box 723)
  - Associated Material
    Associated material consists of envelopes, tags, video covers and notes.
    - Material associated with video recordings, 1994-2004; 12 (Box 724)
    - Envelopes from films, 1992, undated; 2 (Box 724)
- Objects, 1954-2000; Series VI; 1.94; (6 boxes)
  Series VI is organized into two subseries: Photography Related and Personal Effects.
  This series consists of the items Morath used as a photographer, including a camera, film canisters, and rubber ink stamps used to mark her prints, as well as other personal effects, including scarves and a suitcase.
  - Photography Related
    - Leica M3 camera, circa 1954 (Box 733)
    - Film canisters, undated; 40 (Box 734)
    - Film canisters, undated; 29 (Box 735)
    - Rubber stamps, undated; 18 (Box 736)
      Morath used the rubber stamps to mark her photographic prints
  - Personal Effects
    - Silk scarves, undated; 2 (Box 737)
    - Black suitcase, undated (Box 738)
- Printed Material, 1952-2002; 20.92; (30 boxes)
  Printed material is chiefly organized into two groups: Travel, Language and Ephemera and General Books. It also includes Material Found in Books and The Last Journey portfolio.
  Printed material consists of books, periodicals, and other published material by or about Morath and her work, as well as travel and language books used by her.
  - Travel, Language, and Ephemera Publications
    This group of printed material consists of Morath's travel guides, language books, maps and ephemera.
    - Printed material (Box 739)
    - Printed material (Box 740)
    - Printed material (Box 741)
    - Printed material (Box 742)
    - Printed material (Box 743)
    - Printed material (Box 744)
    - Printed material (Box 745)
    - Printed material (Box 746)
    - Printed material (Box 747)
    - Printed material (Box 748)
    - Printed material (Box 749)
    - Printed material (Box 750 (Oversize))
  - Material from Books, 6 (Box 751)
    This group of material consists of notes, maps, postcards, book inserts, brochures, and other printed items found in or filed with books.
  - The Last Journey portfolio, 2001, 2004 (Box 752 (Oversize))
    The Last Journey is a limited edition portfolio created by Branko Lenart that consists of sixteen photographs of Morath and in remembrance of her. A letter to Arthur Miller from Branko Lenart accompanied the portfolio and describes its creation. This portfolio is number two of ten
  - General Books
    Books, periodicals, and other printed material about Morath and her work.
    - Books (Box A)
    - Books (Box B)
    - Books (Box C)
    - Books (Box D)
    - Books (Box E)
    - Books (Box F)
    - Books (Box G)
    - Books (Box H)
    - Books (Box I)
    - Books (Box J)
    - Books (Box K)
    - Books (Box L)
    - Books (Box M)
    - Books (Box N)
    - Books (Box O)
    - Books (Box P)